Next, we're going to talk about classes, objects, and object-oriented programming.
Object-oriented programming, it allows us to represent in a code in a much different way,
organized into classes. The concept of object-oriented programming, it's a language model or a paradigm,
where properties or behaviors are organized into objects. Some programming languages, they
encourage a more procedural style, where you just, you know, like cobalt or basic. You just go through
each thing step by step. You're not jumping to other parts of the program necessarily. But more
modern languages, they tend to adopt a object-oriented style to organize things into objects and provide
methods for those objects to communicate with each other. So what is an object?
It can be, in Python, it can be a function, it could be a variable, a property, it could be a
class. Everything in Python is an object. It's a very important concept. When you think of some
typed languages like Java, it has these, what you can think of primitive types, like an int.
And that is just kind of a very barebow and kind of more down to the level type of type. It doesn't
it's not an object. Whereas in Python, as we saw, even the integers, they're an object. You can
call a method on them. So in Python, everything is an object. You can think of these objects that
are going to make kind of like a generic container, like we can even make our own objects that
maybe look something like a list. To do that, you would have to use magic methods, which I'm
not going to cover today, but something to keep in mind. And if you wanted to make
your object that looks kind of like a list, you might have some helper methods on it. Like
code that might be executed on the whole list, or maybe some of the items on the list, just
to wait to group these concepts together. Python buys pretty heavily into this object oriented
model, but that doesn't mean that you always have to use objects or classes in your programs.
Python also, as we've seen, works perfectly fine in a procedural sort of way.
You know, like a scripting language, where one command is just executed one after the other, like
a recipe. But as you get familiar with object oriented programming, as you read more
Python code written by other people, they'll really learn to help you encapsulate your thinking
and encapsulate your code into objects for better organization and rehability and reuse
and maintainability. Code maintainability is always important. So objects in Python,
there's center stage representing not just the data, but the overall structure of your programs.